Feelings get you killed.
Appaloosa is a drama, western, crime film directed by Ed Harris.
Two friends hired to police a small town that is suffering under the rule of a
rancher find their job complicated by the arrival of a young widow.
Everett Hitch, played by Viggo Mortensen.
Virgil Cole, played by Ed Harris.
Allie, played by Renée Zellweger.
Randall Bragg, played by Jeremy Irons.
Phil Olson, played by Timothy Spall.
Katie, played by Ariadna Gil.
Appaloosa is a 2008 American Western film based on the 2005
novel Appaloosa by crime writer Robert B.
Directed by Ed Harris and co-written by Harris and Robert Knott, Appaloosa stars
Harris alongside Viggo Mortensen, Renée Zellweger, and Jeremy Irons.
The film premiered at 2008 Toronto International Film Festival and was released in selected
cities on September 19, 2008, then expanded into wide release on October 3, 2008.
This movie has won four different awards, including
the Western Heritage Award in 2009.
The film explores themes of small town, new mexico, ranch, cowboy, far west.
The tone is emotional.